Got Dave tonight. Good to see you guys.
All right, so sorry we just just
finished up the seventh round. Obviously
you see the guys are upstairs kind of
finishing up the undrafted process kind
of grinding through that.
You know, we'll add a few guys there not
going to be a huge class of
undrafted guys but we'll have a few of
those guys that we hopefully get locked
up here in the next half hour so
day started
took Caleb Proctor out of defensive
tackle out of Southeast Louisiana.
You know, kind of
came on through the process had a good
really good season this year really
productive season
saw him down at the East West game and
then continued a strong spring process
worked out well
both at the combine and his pro day and
then we had him in here on a 30 visit
enjoyed our time with him there.
And then Reggie Virgil
you know, had a good year this year
Texas Tech had a good season
another guy that we had and enjoyed a
big personality on Reggie and
entertaining guy had him in here on a 30
visit as well
six round Carson Sherar
linebacker out of University of Iowa.
Sorry I got a little allergy thing going
on here.
You know, productive player for Iowa
this year had been a productive special
teams player his whole career.
You know, excited what he can do for us
defensively in the kicking game and then
finished up at the top of the seventh
round with Jaden Williams
offensive tackle from from Ole Miss. So
no movement no trades.
You know, had a couple opportunities
nothing quite got us excited to to move
out on anything. That's way it goes
sometimes but
you know, excited about the the seven
guys we added at the in the undrafted
group. We'll see how that all shakes out
but
you know, I think we added some some
guys are going to help out our our team
and
increase the competition throughout all
levels of the team. So
let it
let you guys fire them at us.
Dave with with a guy like Caleb
how do you kind of go about measuring
what he can be compared to maybe some of
the opposition he might have played out.
I mean you're watching the game tape but
there's there's got to be some
projection right? Yeah, I mean the the
good thing is he played it against LSU
this year. Obviously that's the tape
that everybody's going to go to but he
did play against other schools in the
past. You know,
FBS schools stuff like that and then you
have men in All Star game so you get to
watch it for multiple practices against
bigger school cop.
It's a case where the kid succeeded in
each one of those opportunities and he's
also been able to stack weight. I think
it is pro day he was up into the 290s.
You know, so still tested very well. So
you're seeing some growth potential as
well as being able to compete when you
put them on the same level some of those
bigger school guys. It seemed like
as you guys went through the day you
guys ended up with a lot of players in
this draft class that
were high on that athleticism scale. Is
that something you guys were looking at
or is that just coincidence? I'd say
more coincidence but you know, obviously
like more athletic the better.
Yeah, I've I've seen that I've seen that
used. You know,
you know,
yeah, our guys tested high. That's
that's good. That's good. I wouldn't say
it's it's something that we necessarily
target although you know, whenever we
can add a good athlete that's always a
positive. Are there certain positions
where you see that is maybe more
valuable than others to to have some of
that elite level athleticism testing?
Sure. I mean I think in every position
whenever you know, but I also think you
got to be you be careful.
You know, there's guys that that test
really well and score well on that and
then maybe they put the pads on and they
get on the field and that may not always
translate. So you know, that's that's
one metric.
You know, I would say there there's
plenty of plenty of examples of guys
that that um test pot test highly on
that type of stuff and then that doesn't
translate to the field and the opposite
there's guys that don't test well but
hey when you turn on the tape, you know,
wow this guy's a pretty good athlete. So
it's a it's another piece. One of those
examples of the last thing you were
talking about Reggie was saying that you
told him you were actually happy that he
ran a 457 40 because he might have
slipped down the board. What did he show
you on tape because he's talking about
how he can take the top off defenses.
You don't think that when you see 457.
What did he show you on tape that kind
of made you feel like he has that skill
set? Yeah, I think that's a great
example. I mean you know, when you when
you watch the tape of of Reggie he's
played against high level of competition
this season at Texas Tech and you know,
they played made it into the playoffs
and and played against good teams. I
mean you don't turn on the tape and and
say Reggie's slow. You know, so
in the end that's what matters. Like
there can be guys that run really fast
and test really fast and then they don't
show that on tape and you know, Reggie
when you turn on the tape of Reggie he
he does not play slow. So that's that's
more important is what's on tape. With
Caleb I I saw him listed anywhere
between just right under 6'2 to 6'3.
How will will his height translate to
the NFL can impact what he can do here?
Well, I mean it's really that's where
he's going to have to improve his
technique take the coaching.
You know, you always hear low man wins
and leverage and stuff like that. So if
you have loose hips if you can sink and
bend your knees and your ankles which
Caleb can do it could be a an advantage
to you but you have to have your hand
placement correct. You have to have
enough lower body strength all those
kind of things.
It's not like shorter is necessarily
better but
he's not to the point where he's so
height deficient that he can't play a
certain position or in a scheme. You
know what I mean? And especially rushing
the passer when you have bigger
offensive lineman who might be a little
stiffer trying to get down on you and
you can sink and get around that can be
an asset. You know what I mean?
Obviously
the draft board didn't necessarily fall
to get
an edge type player. Kind of where do
you see the pass rush edge group for you
right now as the roster stands? Yeah, I
mean I think we got we got a lot of guys
there that played a lot of ball between
you know, Sweaty Baron Zaven
you know, BJ
BJ had a you know, tough year last year
coming off the knee and you know, never
really looked quite you know, all the
way back. You know, Jordan Burch going
into his second year. You know, so I
think we have a group and then also
Elliot Brown necko in that and that room
as well. So you know, I think we have a
group that is is a good mix of guys that
have are experienced that played a lot.
You know, and we got to find a way to
put them in the best position. So
obviously always going to look to add
and and increase and and raise the
talent level
but just didn't work out that way to to
add to that group and over the last
three days. A lot of guys are coming
from winning programs. How much stock do
you put into that when you're doing the
evaluation?
I mean it's nice but I you know, I don't
I don't know that that's necessarily a
focal point. You know, but
obviously you like guys that have been
around winning. You like guys that you
know, they're they're obviously coming
from programs that are doing something
right. So that's always good always good
to see guys and then that's going to
help them make that transition
to a higher level of competition. So not
necessarily a focal point but it's also
a nice benefit. With Jaden I know he
played both sides of the line. Is there
a plan to start him out on one side or
just kind of use that versatility to
start off? Yeah, I mean he's he's played
played you know, mainly right tackle but
also saw quite a few snaps at left
tackle as well in his career. I mean I
think some 34 some starts in his career.
So
you know, another guy that
you know, he's played against good
competition in the SEC
but also he's probably blocked as good
of guys in practice like with the
defensive line that they had coming out
of there last year.
He's he's saw good competition
throughout his whole career. So
you know, with the with that with the
tackle position it's it's one that we
work all our guys both sides and that
will be no different for Jaden. Just
going off that you bring back Elijah
Wilkinson. Is that someone you see right
now as a starting right tackle just
given what you guys did in the draft and
other moves? Yeah, I mean Elijah you
know, Elijah started 16 games or
something last year for Atlanta. So
yeah, I think he'll certainly be in the
mix. You know, not really naming
starters anywhere right now but I think
Elijah will definitely have a have a
chance there. Elijah's another guy who
he's played a lot of ball. He's played
at different positions. He started you
know, the first go around with us. He
was inside at guard. He's also played a
lot of tackle in his career. So like the
versatility that he has but yeah, he'll
definitely be in the mix at right
tackle. Day three always seems to be a
little bit more like volatile in terms
of like the the player talent and the
dark horses and
you can find with all of these like
later round guys to have them see the
success they have in the NFL?
No, I just think you know, we have a
pretty good process. We put a lot of
work into it. Him and I Rob Kissel spend
a lot of hours up there watching the
tape of later round guys.
I don't think that's universal through
everybody's draft process where
the top level decision makers pour into
the late rounds as much as they do the
early rounds.
We got a lot of good scouts who have
conviction on some of these guys. We
have an analytics department who helps
guide us. You know, they got their
systems all their different charts their
bells are system whatever they use. But
so we get a lot of input from a lot of
people and we take it seriously. You
know,
as a lifetime scout I hate when people
like ah it's just a six or seven who
cares like really? I can name you a lot
of good players who were found in those
rounds who end up mattering for their
team. So I think as long as you
emphasize it you know, you should be
able to do it pretty well. We talked to
Montez about Carson playing in some high
pressure games and moments.
You have a number of guys who played in
the playoff and then even Caleb's game
at LSU is high pressure. You know, how
do you as a scout kind of evaluate where
do you put playing in big games big
moments on your list of I guess
intangibles and whatnot? Well, I think
it's important like you know, clutch
play you you could label it that but
it's more so you know, you're looking
for matchups too. Who's the guy playing
against? It could be a big game and he's
got a weak opponent and he goes off in
that game but
you know, it's really the matchups of
you know,
Carson Beck's going against Texas A&M's
defense or you know, Ohio State's
defense things like that that you're
looking at as much as what is the stage.
You know what I mean? Along those lines
I think you guys drafted three or four
guys that played in the Shrine Bowl
particularly. You had mentioned earlier
about Proctor you get to see him against
those guys like
the ability to see those guys in those
All Star games against guys that are
going in the draft and maybe
are a little bit higher than even if
they played in a big conference because
those are the best of the best. I mean,
how important are the are those games
and do you guys take
a good chunk of what you're getting out
when you go to these these all-star
games?
Yeah, I I mean, I think any exposure you
get is important. The thing about
all-star games is you get or your scouts
get to go to these games and watch the
guys consecutive practices in a row,
which you don't really do at schools.
You you might hit a school in August,
hit it again in October, hit it again
maybe late November or something, but
they're watching guys practice boom boom
boom.
Uh so, they get a feel for like the
competition. Some guys will improve over
the course of this you know, hey, this
guy's improving if he can do that,
there's more there. And the other thing
is like we have our coaches at these
games. Chris Cook worked the East-West
Shrine Game. He knows Jaden from that
game. So, he can tell us, hey, the guy
was really good in the meeting room. He
learned here here's his technique that
he picked up pretty quickly. I was
teaching him or you know, vice versa.
If it's negative impact, something like
that. I clearly wasn't in that case, but
uh so, that is um very valuable to us,
but it's not necessarily any more
important than any other one, but you
you get a a good experience when you
dial in on that stuff. Dave, with the
Carson Shyre, he was talking about how
much pride he takes in playing special
teams. But in what ways can you see his
linebacker instincts when you play
special teams? Run ahead. I mean, that's
the name of the game. Like you don't see
the guy putting the brakes on before he
runs through somebody's face and that's
what special teams is, you know what I
mean? So,
uh linebacker obviously is a position
where everybody leans on that position
for special teams playing. When a guy
has that background, like you usually
know the guy's tough, you usually know
he'll work hard, whether he can run or
not, like all things that translate to
defense eventually, you know. Marty, you
said your undrafted class won't be very
big. Why
what what goes into that decision? Just
really roster number, you know, our
roster was at a point point where um we
didn't have a ton of room. So, you know,
it's it really comes down to that. I
think we'll be six to eight uh somewhere
in there.
How do you say you approach a draft?
You're very big on like best player
available, but do you go into a draft
thinking, hey, I want to accomplish this
or want to maybe like satisfy this
group? And if you did have any of those
goals, did you accomplish them? Yeah, I
mean, I think I think really the the the
main goal of of any draft is just to
improve the talent level and this is the
biggest um
roster building time of the year. These
three days, you know, that's
um you you know how many players you're
going to be able to add and um there's
no better no bigger time that you get to
add this volume of players. And so, you
know, I think we go in um you know,
having a feel for what our roster having
a feel for what it looks like, but in
the end, all we want to do is add
talent, add competition and just improve
the the construction of our roster
overall. Marty, you said throughout the
off season that you want to kind of
build the foundation for this team, but
you also want to build a team that can
compete in 2026. Where do you kind of
feel like you're at you know, now that
the primary roster building windows of
the off season are done?
Uh yeah, I mean, I like I I I'd I'd say
the roster building never really ends,
you know, it's a it's a constant
evolving.
Um you know, we won't get into too much
competition this spring. There really is
no competition, I should say.
Um that the real competition won't
start, but I mean, there's going to be
players that come available next week
that um you know, because of the draft,
because of free or undrafted free agent
signings, there's going to be another
round of people guys that are come
available. So, um you know, where we at?
I you know, I don't know. We'll see. Our
team hasn't been together. We haven't
practiced one time.
Um you know, we like the players that
we've added in free agency. We like the
players that we've added in the draft.
We think they're going to mel mesh well
with um the the core group that we have
here. Um but we got to get on the grass.
We have we we got to get on the grass
and we got to get a lot of new learning
with uh new coaches and and get our team
together. Um you know, and I know our
guys will be ready to do that. Do you
feel like the roster's in a better place
than it was last season? I do, yeah.
Marty, I'm curious what areas like
specifically? Uh because we've added
good players in free agency and we added
good players in the draft.
Uh last year, Calais was one of the most
prolific defenders in the in the
trenches. So, as you start to get
through the next phases of the off
season, what have your conversations
with him been about maybe playing in
season 19 and if so, if this is a place
he's considering? Yeah, we've uh you
know, we've been in contact with Calais
and we're kind of just you know, wait
and see mode, you know, we'll see. Um
uh he certainly uh earned that right and
uh really enjoyed our year last year
with him and so, you know, we'll see
what that leads to down the road. Is it
hard to for you to look at the what on
paper what you have
and judge it in terms of and then
against what you see on the field? Like
have have you learned to not do that?
Does that Does that make sense? Like
right now you're right now you're
looking at your roster and you know,
like, oh, this is a good team, but you
don't really know how good it is until
you get on the field. Like Is that
something you learned throughout your
career not to do? Is that something you
did earlier you still do it or what? I
mean,
I would say, you know, 31 other teams
are probably looking at their team right
now and saying they've gotten better and
and and have an improved. Um and in all
reality, none of us know, you know, none
of us know until we get out on the field
in September.
Um
and how you know, how we mesh, how we
perform, um
if we stay healthy, like all those
things. So, um
you know, I think everybody can say the
same, but until you're out there
competing and then and when things mean
something, you don't really know.